Adil Shehzad

Jr. DevOps Engineer, Community Builder

Always been a thriller person who gets the work done on time and with perfection. Worked on Linux, Python, JavaScript, Amazon Web Services, Microsoft Azure, Terraform (IaC), Kubernetes RedHat Openshift, Redis, and Serverless Cloud Computing Using AWS Lambda, I am also able to lead and promote a wide variety of community programs and activities to audiences of all ages and ethnic backgrounds.

adil.shehzad4146@gmail.com	
----------------------------	--

+923084146744

Lahore, Pakistan Q

adilshehzad786.github.io/

linkedin.com/in/adilshehzad7 in

github.com/adilshehzad786 🌎

stackoverflow.com/users/12373865/adil-shehzad

medium.com/@adilshehzad786 N

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science University of Central Punjab

09/2017 - Present

WORK EXPERIENCE

DevOps Engineer

Strategic Systems Internationals

09/2021 - Present

DevOps Automation Engineer (Intern)Systems Limited

07/2021 - 09/2021

Lahore

Achievements/Tasks

- Automate the daily tasks using Python Selenium, Web Drivers, Docker & Microsoft Azure Serverless
- Writing Jenkins Automation Scripts Using Bash
- Automate Tasks using Jenkins
- Using Azure Docker Container Instance & Blob Storage for the Jenkins Automation
- Automate the Azure Machines Using Powershell
- Automate Tasks using Serverless Microsoft Container Instances

Terraform Cloud Intern

Microtechx

09/2020 - 01/2021

Lahore, Pakistan

Achievements/Tasks

- Created Azure Hybrid Identity Project
- Docker & Kubernetes Deployment on Azure
- Zero Trust Deployment

Software Quality Assurance (SQA)Afiniti

06/2020 - 09/2020

Lahore,Pakistan

Achievements/Tasks

- Testing and Debugging Software's.
- Reporting Software to the relevant authority.
- Team Leader in Software Quality Department for testing and development of software's.

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

ResumeMate (02/2020 - Present)

 ResumeMate provides professional assistance with a premium template resume. ResumeMate is a non-profit Web Application That Saved User Data on Microsoft Azure Blob, Container and has the ability to Creates a Shareable resume link with a complete userlevel Control panel. ResumeMate has ReactJS Frontend and Django Python Backend.

COMMUNITIES

GitHub Docs Team (Moderator) (05/2021 - Present)

Managing GitHub Docs on GitHub

GitHub Stream Team (04/2021 - Present)

Creating Educational Stuffs for GitHub Education Community.

GitHub Campus Expert (11/2020 - Present)

Building GitHub Community in Pakistan

AWS User Group Lahore Lead (06/2020 - 04/2021)

Leading Cloud Computing Technologies from Pakistan

CERTIFICATES

Chaos Engineering Practitioner (06/2021 - Present)

GitLab Certified Associate (06/2021 - Present)

Scrum Foundation Certified (05/2021 - Present)

Aviatrix MultiCloud Engineer (01/2021 - 01/2024)

LANGUAGES

English

Urdu

Professional Working Proficiency Native or Bilingual Proficiency

INTERESTS

Coding Traveling

Reading Books

Swimming